Guide to the William Mahone Papers, 1853-1895
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1854-1895 (bulk 1879-1892) and undated, 167 containers (72 lin. ft.)
  - 1884, October 25-1884, November 30, (6 folders) (Box 92)
  - 1884, December 1-1885, January 16, (4 folders) (Box 93)
  - 1885, January 17-1885, February 27, (5 folders) (Box 94)
  - 1885, March 1-1885, May 14, (5 folders) (Box 95)
  - 1885, May 15-1885, July 8, (6 folders) (Box 96)
  - 1885, July 9-1885, August 15(6 folders) (Box 97)
  - 1885, August 17-1885, August 31, (4 folders) (Box 98)
  - 1885, September 1-1885, September 21, (4 folders) (Box 99)
  - 1885, September 22-1885 October 7, (5 folders) (Box 100)
  - 1885, October 8-1885, October 20, (6 folders) (Box 101)
  - 1885, October 20-1885, October 31, (5 folders) (Box 102)
  - 1885, November 1-1885, December 31, (5 folders) (Box 103)
  - 1886, January 1-1886, February 28, (5 folders) (Box 104)
  - 1886, March 1-1886, April 19, (5 folders) (Box 105)
  - 1886, April 20-1886, June 20, (6 folders) (Box 106)
  - 1886, June 21-1886, August 31, (5 folders) (Box 107)
  - 1886, September 1-1886, November 30, (6 folders) (Box 108)
  - 1886, December 1-1887, January 31, (6 folders) (Box 109)
  - 1887, February 1-1887, April 14, (6 folders) (Box 110)
  - 1887, April 15-1887, June 30, (5 folders) (Box 111)
  - 1887, July 1-1887, August 13, (5 folders) (Box 112)
  - 1887, August 14-1887, September 11, (6 folders) (Box 113)
  - 1887, September 12-1887, October 5, (6 folders) (Box 114)
  - 1887, October 6-1887, October 31, (6 folders) (Box 115)
  - 1887, November 1-1887, December 31, (5 folders) (Box 116)
  - 1888, January 1-1888, March 31, (6 folders) (Box 117)
  - 1888, April 1-1888, May 19, (5 folders) (Box 118)
  - 1888, May 20-1888, July 31, (7 folders) (Box 119)
  - 1888, August 1-1888, September 7, (6 folders) (Box 120)
  - 1888, September 8-1888, September 30, (7 folders) (Box 121)
  - 1888, October 1-1888, October 22, (8 folders) (Box 122)
  - 1888, October 23-1888, November 8, (7 folders) (Box 123)
  - 1888, November 9-1888, November 30, (7 folders) (Box 124)
  - 1888, December 1-1888, December 22, (7 folders) (Box 125)
  - 1888, December 23-1889, January 12, (7 folders) (Box 126)
  - 1889, January 13-1889, January 31, (6 folders) (Box 127)
  - 1889, February 1-1889, February 25, (7 folders) (Box 128)
  - 1889, February 26-1889, March 17, (6 folders) (Box 129)
  - 1889, March 18-1889, March 31, (5 folders) (Box 130)
  - 1889, April 1-1889, April 10, (5 folders) (Box 131)
  - 1889, April 11-1889, April 22, (6 folders) (Box 132)
  - 1889, April 23-1889, May 6, (6 folders) (Box 133)
  - 1889, May 7-1889, May 23, (6 folders) (Box 134)
  - 1889, May 24-1889, June 10, (6 folders) (Box 135)
  - 1889, June 11-1889, June 30, (6 folders) (Box 136)
  - 1889, July 1-1889, July 16, (5 folders) (Box 137)
  - 1889, July 17-1889, July 26, (6 folders) (Box 138)
  - 1889, July 27-1889, August 5, (7 folders) (Box 139)
  - 1889, August 6-1889, August 13, (5 folders) (Box 140)
  - 1889, August 14-1889, August 23, (7 folders) (Box 141)
  - 1889, August 24-1889, August 31, (8 folders) (Box 142)
  - 1889, September 1-1889, September 9, (7 folders) (Box 143)
  - 1889, September 10-1889, September 15, (6 folders) (Box 144)
  - 1889, September 16-1889, September 21, (7 folders) (Box 145)
  - 1889, September 22-1889, September 30, (5 folders) (Box 146)
  - 1889, September 30-1889, October 6, (5 folders) (Box 147)
  - 1889, October 7-1889, October 12, (5 folders) (Box 148)
  - 1889, October 13-1889, October 17, (5 folders) (Box 149)
  - 1889, October 18-1889, October 23, (7 folders) (Box 150)
  - 1889, October 24-1889, October 28, (6 folders) (Box 151)
  - 1889, October 29-1889, October 31, (7 folders) (Box 152)
  - 1889, November 1-1889, November 16, (6 folders) (Box 153)
  - 1889, November 17-1889, November 30, (6 folders) (Box 154)
  - 1889, December 1-1889, December 31, (9 folders) (Box 155)
  - 1890, January 1-1890, January 31, (9 folders) (Box 156)
  - 1890, February 1-1890, February 28, (7 folders) (Box 157)
  - 1890, March 1-1890, March 31, (7 folders) (Box 158)
  - 1890, April 1-1890, April 30, (3 folders) (Box 159)
  - 1890, May 1-1890, August 30, (8 folders) (Box 160)
  - 1890, September 1-1891, January 31, (6 folders) (Box 161)
  - 1891, February 3-1891, August 31, (7 folders) (Box 162)
  - 1891, September 3-1891, December 31, (6 folders) (Box 163)
  - 1892, January 1-1892, July 29, (6 folders) (Box 164)
  - 1892, August 1-1892, October 31, (5 folders) (Box 165)
  - 1892, November 1-1894, August 30, (6 folders) (Box 166)
  - 1894, September 4-1895, September 22, (7 folders) (Box 167)
- Correspondence Indexes, 1879-1888, 17 volumes. (2 lin. ft.) (Box 167)
  Indexes to the incoming correspondence to Mahone. Inside each volume correspondents' last names are listed alphabetically with a number or numbers beside each name. The numbers indicate what pages in the volumes represent that person's letters to Mahone. One of the volumes for 1881 has on the cover "general applications." Letter writers represented in this volume wrote to Mahone with requests for placement in various governmental positions. Another volume for 1881 indexes letters that are unrelated to position requests.
  The following information is given about each letter noted by the index: 1) who the letter is from; 2) the date; 3) a number; 4) a brief summary; and 5) the place where the letter was written from. This information also appears on the back of the letters themselves. Some of the correspondence dating before 1879 and after 1888 also have this information, but the only indexes in the collection date from 1879 to 1888. One can therefore move easily between the correspondence indexes and the letters for these years. One of the volumes is undated, except for the month and day the letters were written. Volumes are arranged in chronological order.
  - 1879-1881(6 volumes) (Box 168)
  - 1882(3 volumes) (Box 169)
  - 1883-1884,Volume I (3 volumes) (Box 170)
  - 1884,Volume II- 1887,Volume 1 (3 volumes) (Box 171)
  - 1887,Volume 2- 1888(2 volumes) (Box 172)
- Subject Files, 1853-1891 (bulk 1870-1889) and undated, 33 containers (14.5 lin. ft.) (Box 172)
  The Subject File series is arranged alphabetically and primarily relates to Mahone's political and business interests. Many of the topical headings are further subdivided. Politics comprises the bulk of the series and includes the following major subdivisions:
  Appointments, 1870-1890. Includes recommendations, requests, and petitions for people to be assigned to various governmental offices, the most extensive file of which pertains to local post-office positions in Virginia. Other offices and departments represented in this file include the Government Printing Office, the Norfolk Navy Yard and Navy Department, the Treasury Department, the Interior Department, the Internal Revenue Service, and judicial appointments.
  Canvassing, 1880-1889. Contains lists of canvassers, groups to be canvassed, the number of registered voters by political party and often by race, the number of people who voted in previous elections, and the number of people who were delinquent in paying their head tax. This information is usually quite detailed and broken down to the precinct level.
  Elections, 1879-1889. Includes lists of county and city electoral officials, information about election frauds, and election returns, the majority of the material being from 1889 when Mahone ran for governor.
  Financial Papers, 1880-1890. Includes records of campaign expenses for several elections.
  Virginia state conventions, lists of delegates to the state, Conservative (1877), Readjuster (1880, 1881) and Republican (1886, 1892) conventions.
  Printed Material, 1867-1894. Primarily pamphlets and broadsides. Usually the broadsides relate to a particular candidate, meeting, or campaign issue, while the pamphlets concern a variety of issues. Highlighted in the pamphlets is information about the Republican national, state, and district conventions; tariff duties on various items such as sugar and woolens; the Virginia state debt; and the Readjuster movement.
  Another major topic is Railroads. Included is information on several railroads in which Mahone had a financial interest. Among them are the Norfolk and Petersburg, the Orange and Alexandria, and the Virginia and Tennessee railroads. However, the bulk of these files concerns the Atlantic, Mississippi, and Ohio (AMandO) Railroad which Mahone created in 1870. There are extensive files relating to the financial and legal issues surrounding the railroad which suffered an economic setback after the panic of 1873 and went into receivership about 1879. (The railroad was later sold and became known as the Norfolk and Western Railroad.) These files also contain maps of the routes of several railroads and other miscellaneous items pertaining to railroads in general.
  Other topics found in the Subject Files include the Civil War (commissary papers from Mahone's Brigade, 1863 Jan. - Dec.); the Danville Riot, 1883; Richmond Whig (financial records, 1875-1885); the Virginia Military Institute, 1865-1881; the Roanoke Navigation Company, 1880-1892; the American Reduction Company, 1887-1888; and the Carolina Oil and Creosote Company, 1886-1890.
  - Agricultural, Horticultural, and Immigration Association, 1870-1871 (Box 173)
  - American Reduction Company, 1887-1888( 3 folders) (Box 173)
  - Blandford Cemetery (Petersburg, VA), 1876-1878) (Box 173)
  - Carolina Oil and Cresote Company, 1886 August-1890, February, (2 folders) (Box 173)
  - Carolina Oil and Cresote Company: Printed Material 1886-1889 and undated (Box 173)
  - Central Lunatic Asylum (Virginia), 1881-1884 (Box 173)
  - Central Mining, Manufacturing and Land Company, 1891 and undated (Box 173)
  - Civil War: Commissary Papers, 1863, January-1863, December, (5 folders) (Box 174)
  - Civil War: Speeches and Writings, 1871 (Box 174)
  - Civil War: Miscellaneous, 1864-1889 and undated (Box 174)
  - Danville, Virginia: Riot, 1883, (2 folders) (Box 175)
  - Financial Papers: Receipts, 1853-1875, (3 folders) (Box 175)
  - Financial Papers: Receipts, 1875-1882, (6 folders) (Box 176)
  - Financial Papers: Receipts, 1882-1886, (6 folders) (Box 177)
  - Financial Papers: Receipts, 1887-1894 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 178)
  - Financial Papers: Miscellaneous, 1860-1886 and undated (Box 178)
  - Legal Papers, 1872-1886 (Box 178)
  - Game Ridge Mill, 1888 (Box 178)
  - Petersburg Daily News, 1875 (Box 178)
  - Politics: Agriculture Department, 1882 (Box 178)
  - Politics: Appointments, 1881-1884 (Box 178)
  - Politics: Appointments, undated (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Agriculture Department, 1882 July-August and undated (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Census Bureau, 1889 (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Collector of Customs, 1881-1882 (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Government Printing Office 1882 August-October 1884 and undated (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Interior Department, 1882 January-March (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Interior, 1882 April-1889 and undated (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Internal Revenue Service 1880-1889 (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Judicial, 1870-1882 (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Navy Department, 1882 and undated (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Navy Yard, 1881-1889 (Box 179)
  - Politics: Appointments: Navy Yard Scratch Book of Names for Appointment Laborers and Mechanics, (2 folders) (Box 180)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1881 May-1882 February, (6 folders) (Box 180)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1882 March-1882 April, (3 folders) (Box 181)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1882 May-1882 September, (6 folders) (Box 182)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1882 October-1883, February, (6 folders) (Box 183)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1883 March-1883 September, (6 folders) (Box 184)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1883 October-1885 February, (7 folders) (Box 185)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1885 July-1885 December, (6 folders) (Box 186)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1889 (Box 186)
  - Politics: Appointments: Post Office, 1890 and undated (Box 187)
  - Politics: Appointments: Railway Mail Service, 1881-1889 (Box 187)
  - Politics: Appointments: Treasury Department, 1881-1882 and undated (Box 187)
  - Politics: Appointments: U.S. Marshals, 1881-1889 (Box 187)
  - Politics: Appointments: Miscellaneous, 1873-1889 and undated (Box 187)
  - Politics: Cabinet Position for Mahone (proposed), 1889 (Box 187)
  - Politics: Canvassing, 1880 August-1881, October (Box 187)
  - Politics: Canvassing, 1880-1883, September, (7 folders) (Box 188)
  - Politics: Canvassing, 1883 September-1889 October, (5 folders) (Box 189)
  - Politics: Canvassing: Black Churches and Ministers, 1883 (Box 189)
  - Politics: Canvassing: Black Ministers, 1889 (Box 190)
  - Politics:Canvassing: County and District Canvassers, 1888, (2 folders) (Box 190)
  - Politics: Canvassing: Local Canvassers, 1885 (Box 190)
  - Politics: Canvassing: Schedules and Maps for Canvassers, 1882-1887 (Box 190)
  - Politics: Canvassing: Schedules of Canvassers, 1889 (Box 190)
  - Politics: Canvassing: Voters, Mild Democrats, 1887-1888 (Box 190)
  - Politics: Canvassing; Voters, Mild Democrats, 1887-1888 (Box 191)
  - Politics: Canvassing: Miscellaneous, 1888-1889 and undated (Box 191)
  - Politics: Congressional Campaign Club, 1876 and undated (Box 191)
  - Politics: Elections: County Electoral Officials, Recommendations for, 1880, 1882, 1888 (Box 191)
  - Politics: Elections: County Officers, 1883 (Box 191)
  - Politics: Elections: County Officers, 1883 (Box 192)
  - Politics: Elections: Frauds, 1882-1888, (6 folders) (Box 192)
  - Politics: Elections: Frauds, 1889, (5 folders) (Box 193)
  - Politics: Elections, Returns, 1879-1889 and undated, (5 folders) (Box 194)
  - Politics: Tickets, 1885 (Box 194)
  - Politics: U.S. Commissioner: Recommendations for, 1884 (Box 194)
  - Politics: Miscellaneous, 1874-1885 (Box 194)
  - Politics: Financial Papers, 1883-1889 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 194)
  - Politics: Financial Papers: Campaign, 1880, 1890 and undated, (7 folders) (Box 195)
  - Politics: Financial Papers: Subscriptions to the National Commission's Reserve Fund, 1889-1890 and undated (Box 195)
  - Politics: Mailing Lists, 1839-1884 and undated (Box 195)
  - Politics: National Minute Men of America, 1882 (Box 195)
  - Politics: Navy Department, 1882-1883 (Box 195)
  - Politics: Post Office, 1882 (Box 195)
  - Politics: Post Office, 1883-1884, (2 folders) (Box 196)
  - Politics: Post Office Book: W. R. Robinson's, undated (Box 196)
  - Politics: Public Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1882-1887 and undated (Box 196)
  - Politics: Republican Clubs, 1884-1889 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 196)
  - Politics: Chairmen and Committees, 1884-1885 (Box 196)
  - Politics: Republican County Chairmen and Committees, 1885-1886 and undated (Box 196)
  - Politics: Republican Party Leadership, undated (Box 197)
  - Politics: Seed Distribution, 1881 January-1887 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 197)
  - Politics: Speeches and Writings, 1887 and undated (Box 197)
  - Politics: Speeches and Writings of Others, 1879-1885 and undated (Box 198)
  - Politics: Spoils System, 1884-1885 (Box 198)
  - Politics: Tobacco Legislation, 1882-1886 and undated (Box 198)
  - Politics: U.S. District and Circuit Courts for Western District of Virginia, 1882-1884 and undated (Box 198)
  - Politics: Veterans, 1882-1885 (Box 198)
  - Politics: Virginia County, District, Precinct Meetings, 1875-1892 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 198)
  - Politics: Virginia Debt, 1872-1891 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 198)
  - Politics: Virginia State Convention: Delegates Conservative Convention Notebook, 1877, (2 folders) (Box 199)
  - Politics: Virginia State Convention: Readjuster Delegates, 1880-1881, (3 folders) (Box 199)
  - Politics: Virginia State Convention: Republican Congressional Convention, 1886 (Box 199)
  - Politics: Virginia State Convention: Roll of Delegates to State Republican Convention, 1892 (Box 199)
  - Politics: Printed Material, 1867-1881, (2 folders) (Box 199)
  - Politics: Printed Material, 1882-1894 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 200)
  - Politics: Miscellaneous, 1876-1885 (Box 200)
  - Politics: Miscellaneous, 1886-1892 and n.d (Box 201)
  - Railroads: Financial Papers: Miscellaneous, 1873-1876 and undated (Box 201)
  - Railroads: Specifications, 1872 and undated (Box 201)
  - Railroads: Atlantic, Mississippi and Ohio: General Information, 1875-1876 and undated (Box 201)
  - Railroads: Atlantic, Mississippi and Ohio: Financial Papers, 1870-1882 and undated (Box 201)
  - Railroads: Atlantic, Mississippi and Ohio: Legal Papers, 1870-1876 August (Box 201)
  - Railroads: Atlantic, Mississippi and Ohio: Legal Papers, 1876 September-1881 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 202)
  - Railroads: Atlantic, Mississippi and Ohio: Miscellaneous, 1867-1889 and undated (Box 202)
  - Railroads: Atlantic, Mississippi and Ohio: Clippings, 1876-1880 (Box 202)
  - Railroads: B-New York (Box 202)
  - Railroads: Norfolk and Edenton (Box 202)
  - Railroads: Norfolk and Petersburg: Financial Papers, 1853-1884 and undated (Box 202)
  - Railroads: Norfolk and Petersburg: Legal Papers, 1861-1868 and undated (Box 202)
  - Railroads: Norfolk and Petersburg: Clippings, 1853 (Box 202)
  - Railroads: Norfolk and W-N (Box 203)
  - Railroads: Orange and Alexandria R.R. Co. 1849-1851 (Box 203)
  - Railroads: Petersburg Railroad Company, 1872-1873 (Box 203)
  - Railroads: R-Southern... (Box 203)
  - Railroads: Southside R.R. Co., 1867-1877 (Box 203)
  - Railroads: Virginia and Kentucky, 1857-1876 and undated (Box 203)
  - Railroads: Virginia and Tennessee Railroad Company, 1871-1874 (Box 203)
  - Railroads: Wilmington and Raleigh Railroad Company (Box 203)
  - Railroads: Miscellaneous, 1852-1888 and undated (Box 203)
  - Richmond Whig: Financial Papers, 1885-1880, (3 folders) (Box 203)
  - Richmond Whig: Financial Papers, 1879 June-1875 December, (5 folders) (Box 204)
  - Richmond Whig: Mailing List, 1877 (Box 204)
  - Roanoke Navigation Company, 1880-1892 and undated (Box 205)
  - S. V. White and Co. (Box 205)
  - Southwest Virginia Improvement Company, 1889-1890 and undated (Box 205)
  - Virginia Military Institute, 1865-1881 (Box 205)
  - Miscellaneous, 1871-1889 and undated, One half of a container (.2 lin. ft.) (Box 205)
    Includes specifications for a fountain to be built in Mahone's honor, an obituary for Mahone's nine year old daughter, Elise, social invitations, unidentified photographs, architectural drawings, and a few other items.
  - Clippings, 1872-1892 and undated, One half of a container (.2 lin. ft.) (Box 205)
    Chiefly articles related to political issues and concerns in Virginia including the state debt and the rival political parties the Readjusters and Funders, many from the Richmond Whig. Also articles (1886) about John Goode of Virginia who was rejected by the United States Senate for Solicitor General of the United States and articles concerning Mahone in 1889 when he ran for governor of Virginia.
- Scrapbooks, 1868-1889, 41 vols. (10 lin. ft.) (Box 205)
  Forty-one scrapbooks primarily containing clippings but also including circular letters, broadsides, and a few handwritten notes. In the container listing, the dates that have been given on the cover of the scrapbooks are noted. However, the period covered by the scrapbooks does not always match the dates that appear on the scrapbooks' covers. All but three are stored in boxes. The three not in boxes are oversized and shelved immediately after the boxed scrapbooks. Loose items found in the scrapbooks were placed in folders and are filed in the boxes with the scrapbooks.
  Topics primarily concern local and state political matters in Virginia, many relating to Mahone. Among the chief topics are the rise of the Readjuster movement and early efforts to organize the Readjusters into a state political party; the state debt; the free school system; Virginia state, district, and county conventions; canvassing voters; Mahone's election to the United States Senate in 1880; the Danville Riot in 1883; support for Mahone to be appointed to a post in Benjamin Harrison's cabinet; Mahone's gubernatorial race in 1889; and the schism which developed in the Virginia Republican Party in the late 1880s. Many of the broadsides announce political speeches.
  To a lesser degree, materials about railroads are also included, particularly materials relating to the controversial consolidation of railroads in Virginia and the financial difficulties of the Atlantic, Mississippi, and Ohio Railroad.
  - No. 1B, 1870-1871, 1876, 1882 (Box 206)
  - No. 1B (folder) (Box 206)
  - No. 2A, 1870 (Box 206)
  - No. 2B, 1871-1873 (Box 206)
  - No. 2B (folder) (Box 206)
  - No. 3, 1866-1875 (Box 207)
  - No. 5, 1878-1881 (Box 207)
  - No. 6, 1879 (Box 207)
  - No. 7, 1877 (Box 208)
  - No. 7, (folder) (Box 208)
  - No. 8, 1877 (Box 208)
  - No. 8 (folder) (Box 208)
  - No. 9, 1879 (Box 208)
  - No. 9 (folder) (Box 208)
  - No. 10, 1879 (Box 209)
  - No. 10 (folder) (Box 209)
  - No. 11, 1880 Senatorial Scraps (Box 209)
  - No. 12, 1880 "Funder Record" (Box 209)
  - No. 13, 1880 (Box 210)
  - No. 13 (folder) (Box 210)
  - No. 14, 1880 (Box 210)
  - No. 14 (folder) (Box 210)
  - No. 15, 1880-1881 Public Debt, Vote of 1880 (Box 211)
  - No. 15 (folder) (Box 211)
  - No. 16, 1880 (Box 211)
  - No. 17, 1880-1881 (Box 211)
  - No. 18, 1880-1881 (Box 212)
  - No. 19, 1881 (Box 212)
  - No. 19 (folder) (Box 212)
  - No. 20, 1881 (Box 212)
  - No. 20 (folder) (Box 212)
  - No. 21, 1881 (Box 213)
  - No. 21 (folder) (Box 213)
  - No. 22, Campaign Documents 1881 (Box 213)
  - No. 22 (folder) (Box 213)
  - No. 23 The Whig on Daniel 1881 [John W. Daniel member of the Funders] (Box 213)
  - No. 24, 1881 (Box 214)
  - No. 25, 1881 Brown, Ga. [Joseph E. Brown Senator and Governor of Georgia] (Box 214)
  - No. 26, 1881 (Box 214)
  - No. 27, Massey, 1882 [John E. Massey] (Box 214)
  - No. 28, Liberal Movement, 1882 (Box 215)
  - No. 28 (folder) (Box 215)
  - No. 29, 1882 (Box 215)
  - No. 30, 1882 (Box 215)
  - No. 30 (folder) (Box 215)
  - No. 31, 1883 Danville Riot and Newspaper Comments (Box 216)
  - No. 31 (folder) (Box 216)
  - No. 32, Campaign 1884 (Box 216)
  - No. 32 (folder) (Box 216)
  - No. 33, 1884-1885 (Box 217)
  - No. 33 (folder) (Box 217)
  - No. 35, 1886 (Box 217)
  - No. 35 (folder) (Box 217)
  - No. 36, 1887-1888 (Box 217)
  - No. 36, (2 folders) (Box 217)
  - No. 37 1888 State Convention, Chicago Convention, Wise, Houston, Brady, etc. (Box 218)
  - No. 37 (folder) (Box 218)
  - No. 38, Campaign 1888 (Box 218)
  - No. 38, (2 folders) (Box 218)
  - No. 40, 1889 (Box 219)
  - No. 40 (folder) (Box 219)
  - No. 1a, 1868-1870 (Box 220)
  - No. 1a (folder) (Box 220)
  - No. 34, Campaign Circulars of 1885 (Box 221)
  - No. 34 (folder) (Box 221)
  - No. 39, 1889, Clippings relating to Cabinet Resolutions and c. from Counties and Cities (Box 221)
  - No. 41 (folder) (Box 221)
  - Nos. 41, 42-43, undated Three oversize scrapbooks, nos. 41, 42-43 are shelved at the end of the boxed scrapbooks (Box 221)
  - Profile of Report of a Survey made by Maj. Walter Gwynn from Norfolk to Edenton, NC (Box 222)
- Oversize Materials (Box 222)
  - Chiefly maps, including those of railroad routes, (2 folders) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:1, Box 222)
  - Financial records of the Atlantic, Mississippi and Ohio Railroad and miscellaneous railroad and political papers, (4 folders) (Box 223)
  - Miscellaneous political and railroad papers, (2 folders) (Box Oversz. Box 7)